Ralston, Jennie Craven mss., 1894-1950 LMC 1883
Lilly Library
Ralston, Jennie Craven mss.
1894-1950
Lilly Library
Ralston, Jennie Craven, 1861-1954
LMC 1883
3 Boxes 2 standard, 1 custom
The Ralston, Jennie Craven mss., 1894-1950, consists of the papers of Indiana's Democratic National Committeewoman and wife of Samuel Moffett Ralston, Indiana Governor and US Senator, Jennie Craven Ralston, 1861-1954.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research.
Many collections are housed offsite; retrieval requires advance notice. Please make an appointment a minimum of one week in advance of your visit.
Biographical Note
Jennie Craven Ralston, 1861-1954, was born in Danville, Indiana and attended Central Normal College, graduating in 1881. She met Samuel M. Ralston while in school and they were married in 1889, living in Lebanon, Indiana. A driven leader, Ralston held positions as a Trustee of the Indiana Girls School, Vice-President of the Indiana Federation of Clubs, and was Indiana's Democratic National Committeewoman from 1934 to 1953.
For more biographical information, see The Lost Mrs. Ralston on the Indiana History Blog.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged chronologically.
Scope and Content Note
The manuscripts consist of letters from prominent political figures, friends, and members of the family, and poetry, prose writings, and speeches by Ralston. Included also are miscellaneous pamphlets, newspaper clippings pertaining to Ralston, and Democratic National Committee material, 1924-1949.
Related Material
See Ralston, B.M.K. mss., Ralston, J.C. mss., and Ralston, S.M. mss., also located at the Lilly Library, Indiana University, Bloomington, Indiana.
Acquisition Information
Gift: 1954
Indiana--Politics and government; United States—Politics and government—20th century; Women; Democratic National Committee member; Letters; Poetry.; Newspapers; Ralston, Jennie Craven, 1861-1954; Ralston, Samuel Moffett, 1857-1925; Ralston, Julian Craven, 1895-1935
- 1894-1906 (Box 1)
- 1907-1924 (Box 1)
- Diary, 1924 (Box 1)
- 1925-1950 (Box 1)
- Correspondence, undated (Box 1)
- Writings, undated, (5 folders) (Box 1)
- Printed
  - Pamphlets (Box 1)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1924-1948 (Box 1)
  - Democratic National Committee, 1949 (Box 1)
  - Newspaper clippings and broadside, 1906-1945 (Box 1)